Profile

Skilled and results-oriented Web Software Engineer with more than eight years of experience. Strong in design and integration of problem-solving skills. Professional in developing business plans, requirements specifications, user documentation, and architectural systems research. Strong written and verbal communications.

Work experience

Technical Lead & Development Nesma Holding, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia 06/2019 - present

- System Analysis and Integration.
- Architect/Lead/Developer and Responsible for end to end product development.
- Defined all processes used by team change management, review, unit test, coding standard, etc.
- Design the features and usability flow.
- Performed risk analysis and developed mitigation strategies.
- Prepared the Functional Requirement Document by coordinating with software team.
- Used coding methods in specific programming languages to initiate and improve program execution and functionality.

Senior Airline Applications
Integration Specialist

10/2016 - 05/2019

Nesma Airlines, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia

- Development of automation software for Airline departments.
- Full stack development of various modules.
- Implementation of new projects, the integration of existing services.
- Implementing application change requests according to the standard change process.
- Training new team members.
- Assist in the definition of project scope and objectives, involving all relevant stakeholders and ensuring technical feasibility.
- Worked closely with Project Managers(budget, reimbursements).
- Understanding the requirements through the Functional Design Documents and preparing Technical Design documents.
- Understand the project needs and plan for development in server side implementation.

Senior / Web application developer 06/2012 – 10/2016

eDesign, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia

- Designed, developed and maintained web-based applications.
- Developed front-end and back-end of web applications.
- Identified and eliminated website bugs to improve user experience.
- Interacted with business customers to understand their needs, present website demos, hear their queries, and resolved technical issues arising during projects.
- Managing multiple databases in a highly scalable project.

Bilal Ur Rahman



Personal info

- **1** 07/12/1990
- Pakistani
- bilal.ur.rahman@hotmail.com
- +966541164696
- ♠ Qays Ibn Khalid, Jeddah 23232, Saudi Arabia
- shorturl.at/stCN9

Skills

Development Skills

.NET	••••
MVC	••••
00P	••••
Web Services	••••
HTML & CSS	••••
Javascript	••••
PHP	••••
React	••••
Angular	00000
Firebase	••••

DevOps & Cloud

CI/CD	••••
Docker	••••
Jenkins	••••
Circle CI	••••
Oracle Cloud	00000
Infrastructure	

Database

MS SQL	••••
MYSQL	••••
Stored Procedures	••••
Mongo DB	••••

Work experience

• Mentored junior developer, elicited requirements, conducted usability testing, performed most aspects of Technical Lead and Project Manager roles.

Education

BS Computer Science 01/2008 - 04/2012 University of Karachi, Karachi, Pakistan

Achievements

- 1. Developed & assist in payment gateway integration for Nesma Airlines.
- 2. Assisted in implementation & maintained SADAD payment gateway integration in (www.nesmaairlines.com)
- 3. Tech lead in integration of airline applications and other systems (Yakeen, SITA, MOI & GACA).
- 4. Tech lead in implementation of APIs that communicates(GET,PUSH) with all other airline applications.
- 5. Auto **Migration tool** implemented for (migrating data to new software applications)
- 6. Worked with team in implementing IT Applications Rules and Policy.
- 7. Tech lead and developer in intranet Portal application for Nesma Holding & Subsidiaries (using **G-Suite APIs**).
- 8. Tech lead and Architect in Implementing internal Entertainment application.
- 9. Tech lead in designing architecture of Central CMS for Nesma(Service Oriented Architecture).
- 10. Architect and Implemented automation tool for data migration.
- 11. Architect and implement **Token security system** in JCEA. (http://eservices.jcci.org.sa)
- 12. Letter Attestation mechanism implementation for JCEA.
- 13. Implementation and maintained (http://www.alkhorayef.com/)
- 14. Assisted, and maintained Nesma Group websites (www.nesma.com, www.mpcpro.com/, www.nesmawae.com)

Certificates

PeopleCert GR671142167BU

524847f8629c4e9c9236b66d8c56d3fc

Hobbies







Love to travel

moments

Capturing Sports Fan





Video Book Games Worm

Social Media





